(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-11T23:13:34.745643",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
また悪い夢を見た。
Another bad dream.
陰惨な現場が日常の探偵という職業には、悪夢は付き物と言ってもいいでしょう。
Perhaps nightmares are the penalty a detective pays for being in a gruesome business.
だが、気にしている場合ではない。
So be it. She's not about to stop.
彼女のもとに、また新たな事件が舞い込んできているからだ。
Not when there are new cases to be solved.
Unhappy? 悩める人の子よ
Unhappy? If you're dealing with a lotta woes
Unlucky? 人成らざる者も
Unlucky? Then you gotta listen very close
Be happy 弛まず目指せよ 生きているんだし
Be happy! Keep on trying, never give up / Don't forget that you're alive
目を逸らした過去も 退屈な未来も
The past you have been running from / That boring future yet to come
カウンセリング やれやれ
Still counseling you / Oh my, oh my
古今東西 ピースピース
Universal, peace, peace yeah
Unhappy? Unlucky?
Be happy!
Undead!
ねえ 何だかどうして戦ってるような そんな気がするの
Somehow feeling like there's a fight within and it's been going on so long
触れられない 触れたくもない過去の自分
I don't feel it and don't even wanna try / Past version of me
自分 自分 自分ともう とっくに死んでる透明な亡霊と対決
Of me, of me, of me and those figures of the old / Transparent ghosts over my route
幼気で痛い記憶の奥
The childish and painful memories have the deepest roots
残念？もう居ないのに
Saddening? Nowhere to be seen
あれ？そっちが良い？アイロニーね
Say what? Way better then? Irony
透かされているのは現在の自分？
They all see the me of the past when looking at me now
ナンセンス 消えないレッテル
Nonsense, label I can't erase
Yes! 要はコンプレックス
Yes! In essence, a complex
取り憑かれているみたい 巻き付いたまままだ離れない
It's almost like something's possessing me / It is wrapping tight around and won't loosen its bounds
在りし日の自分
The self I used to be before
Undead!
死んじゃいない
Still alive
お前とお前の連鎖
Time is a chain of your own path
生きていることは変わり続けることだ
To be alive is to always embrace your inner changes, on and on
不幸に甘んじて満足するなよ
Don't settle for unhappiness / Don't be complacent in distress
幸せになろうとしないなんて卑怯だ
Not even trying to seize the joy and be happy, you coward
この世 この世は奇怪 奇怪ファンタジー
Oh, this world, oh, this world is one odd, one odd fantasy
次は鬼が出るか蛇が出るか
Who knows what is coming up next, a monster or a snake?
出会って 遭って やっと始まる物語さ
This story starts after that encounter, finally
さあ 人か化物か 閑話休題 ピースピース
With people or monsters and spirits / Back on topic, peace, peace yeah
Past & future
Can't change the past
Run for the future
カットイン
Cutting in
ねえ 何だかどうして未来になんぞ何の希望もない
Somehow feeling like there's nothing to be looking forward to
期待出来ないような気がして もう随分生きている
No hope to find, cannot be defined / Lived long enough, nothing is new
既視感とテンプレで食傷 素敵な出来事の気配もない
There's nothing left to view / No sign of anything wonderful waiting down the line
残念 積んだ経験の因果 形骸化された神話と退屈な進化
Saddening, too much knowledge results in feeling like every myth is but another boring evolution
要は刺激が欲しいんだ
Thrill is what I really want now
飽きちゃった 慣れちゃった
Bored and down, used to frowns
なんて整っていくガイダンス
And this is the way the guidance grew
増えるコンプライアンス
Rising compliance too
蓋されていくみたい 吸い尽くして
It's like I'm going under a lid / I consumed everything
あれもこれもどれも同じ味がする
This one, or that one, or whichever / And now, it all just tastes the same
おなじ味がする
They all taste the same.
(Undead!)
死んじゃいない お前とお前の連鎖
You are not dead, the chain of you and yourself.
いつの世も 過去も未来も 今にあるんだ
In any era, past and future, they exist in the present.
生きていることを 愚直に果たせよ
Fulfill your life with foolish honesty.
目指せ ハッピーエンド
Aim for a happy ending.
(Undead!) 死んじゃいない
(Undead!) You are not dead.
お前に言っているんだ 幸せを諦めてしまうな
I'm telling you, never give up on your happiness.
ただ苦しみに慣れて 耐えているだけじゃ
If you just get used to suffering and endure it,
死んでいるのも同然 屍同然
you are as good as dead, just like a corpse.
Unhappy? 悩める人の子よ
Unhappy? Oh child of woes,
Unlucky? 人ならざる者も
Unlucky? Even non-humans too,
Be happy 弛まず目指せよ
Be happy, aim sleeplessly,
生きているんだろう
for you are alive, right?
ぽっかり減ったままの 幸せになるのも
Whether to remain empty or to become happy,
全部全部 お前の...
it's all, all on your...
Past and future, can't change the past.
Past and future, run for the future.
減ったところをともに埋めいこう
Let's fill the empty spaces together,
生き抜くこの 化け物ばかりの 物語に
in this story full of monsters we survive through.
Oh oh oh...
ダメ ダメ ダメ 脳みその中から
No, no, no... From deep inside my brain,
「やめとけバカ」と叫ぶんだ
morality screams, "Stop it, you idiot!"
ダーリン、ダーリン、ダーリン
Darlin', darlin', darlin'...
半端なく ラブと煌めき
with insane love and sparkling sparkles,
明日をフィロソフィー
tomorrow is a philosophy.
死ぬほど可愛い上目遣い
Your look up is so adorable it could kill,
何が必要に触れるくらい
scattering just enough to touch my core,
ばらまくラッシュ
a scattering rush.
気付けば陶酔
Before I knew it, I was in ecstasy.
この世に生まれた君が悪い
It's your fault for being born into this world.
いっそしんどい 声に出したい
I'd rather let out this painful love,
恋はすれ違い
but we pass each other by.
バラバラ濡れた頭とこの瞬間
My head is in pieces, soaked in this very moment,
転落を免れない 愛を味方にして
we can't escape the fall. With love on our side,
アリスアウト
it's iris out.
いっそどうしよう この想いはどうしよう
What on earth should I do with these feelings?
あばらの奥の ザラメが溶けて
In the back of my ribs, sugar crystals melt,
ゲロになりそう
ready to turn into puke.
瞳孔バチ開いて 溺れ死にそう
With pupils fully dilated, I feel like drowning to death.
今この世で君だけが 大正解
Right now, in this world, you are the only correct answer.
ダーリン、ダーリン...
Darlin', darlin'...
ひっくり返っても おかしいようない
Even if I flip over, it wouldn't be strange.
君だけルールは手遅れがい
Rules don't apply to you, it's too late.
四つとも黒しかない 勝ち逃げ放題
Only four black pieces left, you win and run as you please.
君が笑顔で放った アバダケダブラで
With the Avada Kedavra you shot with a smile,
おでこにステッカーも 申し訳ねえな
leaving a sticker on my forehead, my bad.
矢を射して 貫いて すっごく奥深く
Shoot me with an arrow, pierce me, deep inside.
死ぬほど可愛い上腕二頭筋
Your biceps are so adorable it could kill,
何が必要に触れるくらい
scattering just enough to touch my core,
ばらまくラッシュ
a scattering rush.
気付けば陶酔 この世に生まれた君が悪い
Before I knew it, I was in ecstasy. It's your fault for being born into this world.
足掻いても 何でもいい 今君となぞっている
Struggling or whatever, it doesn't matter. Right now I'm tracing...
すべてほしい 頸動脈なアイラブユーが切れて
I want it all. The carotid artery of 'I love you' bursts,
アリスアウト
iris out.
Ah ah ah...
いっそどうしよう この想いはどうしよう
What on earth should I do with these feelings?
あばらの奥の ザラメが溶けて
In the back of my ribs, sugar crystals melt,
ゲロになりそう
ready to turn into puke.
瞳孔バチ開いて 溺れ死にそう
With pupils fully dilated, I feel like drowning to death.
今この世で君だけが 大正解
Right now, in this world, you are the only correct answer.
ダーリン、ダーリン...
Darlin', darlin'...
アリスアウト
iris out.
ある殺人事件を調べてほしいという匿名の依頼。
An anonymous plea for help in the investigation of a murder.
手紙に被害者の情報はほとんどなく、ましてや犯人の情報は皆無であった。
The letter had little on the victim and nothing on the killer.
あまりに不可解な謎の手紙。
A letter too mysterious and cryptic.
イタズラの可能性もある、けど...
It could even be a prank, but...
おや？
Huh?
おはよう、アーニャ！依頼された絵が完成しましたよ〜。
Good morning, Anya! I finished your commission~
一伊那尓栖（にのまえ　いなにす）。
Ninomae Ina'nis.
この町一番の肖像画家だ。
The greatest portrait artist on this side of the tracks.
あの...私の顔に何か付いてます？
Um... is there something on my face?
事件の手がかりがない以上、解決の糸口を見つけるには彼女の才能を頼る必要があった。
With no leads, the detective needed a talent like that to jumpstart her investigation.
アーニャ？
Anya?
とは言えこういった事件では、誰もが容疑者になりうる。
Then again, in a case like this, anyone could be the killer.
そう、この純粋で可憐なイナでさえ...
What if sweet, innocent Ina—
わぁあっ！
WAH!
うわっ！
Ah!
ごめんなさい。じーっと見られてたからつい...どうかしましたか？
Sorry, but you were just staring at me. Is everything okay?
いや別に...それっぽい雰囲気を出そうとしてただけ。
Yeah, I'm just building atmosphere.
それより、頼んでた絵はできた？
Uh, anyway, you did the picture I asked for?
できました〜！
Yeah!
これ、誰の肖像画なんですか？
Who's this a picture of anyway?
なんでこの子の絵なんですか？
いま調べている事件の被害者だよ。
The victim from a case I'm working.
あっ、報酬はいつもの値段でいいよね？
Anyway, you're charging the standard fee, right?
悪いけど今回はツケにしといて。
Sorry, but can you put it on my tab?
でも前回もツケって言ってましたよね…。
But you put the last one on your tab too...
じゃあイナは特別に…1回だけタダで依頼を受けてあげるから。
Maybe we could do a trade then? I'll solve one case for you for free.
それよりも…歌がいいな～。
Oooorrr... I'll trade you for a song~
はい？
Huh?
だって！アーニャさん最近ずっと怖い顔してますよ。たまには息抜きしないと。
Come on! You've been so serious lately. You gotta get loose sometimes.
私と1曲歌ってくれたら、絵は差し上げます。どうですか？
So one song with me, and you get to keep the picture. That's the deal~
そこまで言うなら…歌ってやるか！
If that's what you want, then alright!
大きな白いキャンバスに 虚構のコラージュを貼るよ
On a big white canvas, I paste a collage of fiction
どこからでもキレイに映る 誇張された天使が居たよ
There was an exaggerated angel that looked stunning from every angle
薔薇 人 歪んだ 正しくなくても見えた
A rose, a person distorted, even if they weren't right I could still see them
生きるため立ち寄った 美術館のセザンヌに
In the Cézanne at the art museum I stopped by to stay alive
なん も わかん ない な まだ 知らず に いても 描け た
I don't understand anything, but even without knowing I managed to paint
赤 ずっと 塗り 込ん だ バカ きっと そう だった
I kept plastering red all over — idiot, I surely did
ヒド い筆の 絵画 だけど そこがいいな
A painting with terrible brushwork, but that's what's good about it
くだらない 線 だな そのまま ああ
Such meaningless lines, just as they are, ah
切って貼った皮 裂いて見えた痣
The skin that's cut and pasted, the bruises seen when torn
ララ ラン ラララ 笑う ように 浮いた アバラ
La la lan lalala, floating ribs that seem to laugh
ぎゅっ て 抱い た 空 だって 泣い た から
I held the emptiness tight, because I had cried
ララ ラン ラララ なげく 壁 に 描い た パブロー・ピカソ
La la lan lalala, painted on the grieving wall — Pablo Picasso
なぜか わたしの こと だなって 眺めちゃったよ
Somehow I found myself thinking "this is about me", as I gazed
これが欲しいなって感じたの セザンヌの絵をキボンヌ なんてね
It made me feel "I want this" / Like "I wanna seize a Cézanne!", just kidding
老人がとなりでじっと見てたよ
An old man beside me was staring
欺瞞 ウソ 若さ ならば 本物の意味あるのかな
Deception and lies — if it's youth / I wonder if there's any meaning to the real thing
真実抱いたまま 腐り落ちて床で死んでた
Whilst holding the truth in your arms, it rotted away and died on the floor
赤 ずっと 塗り 込ん だ やっぱ ずっと 良かった
I kept plastering red all over — that was the best after all
イヤ らしい 線 だな 今 もう ああ
Such nasty lines, even now, ah
切って貼った皮 咲いて散った花
The skin that's cut and pasted, the flowers bloomed and scattered
ララ ラン ラララ 笑う ように 見えた カラダ
La la lan lalala, a body that seems to laugh
ぎゅっ て 抱い た 空 だって 泣い た から
I held the emptiness tight, because I had cried
ララ ラン ラララ なげく 壁 に 描い た パブロー・ピカソ
La la lan lalala, painted on the grieving wall — Pablo Picasso
わたし ウソ の ピカソ
I, the Picasso of lies
やっと来た。
Finally.
こんな不気味な場所で待たせないでほしいんだけど。
This is a creepy place to make someone wait.
現場を調べたらKFPの近くに寄るから、店の近くで待っててって言ったのに。
I told you I'd come to the nearby KFP after investigating the crime scene.
そんなの無理！
Not a chance!
アンタと話すだけでもイヤなのに、話してるところを人に見られたらそれこそ最悪。
It's bad enough I have to talk to you. I don't want others to be around to see it.
そんなアンタが手を貸してくれるなんて意外だけどね。
I'm surprised you're willing to cooperate in the first place.
それは…例の殺人事件以降、いろいろ妙なことが起こってるの。
Yeah, well, ever since the murder, weird things have been happening.
アンタが解決してくれるなら、こうやって会うのもやむなしよ。
I figure if you can help solve it, then it's worth the trouble of meeting with you.
イヤだけど。
Just barely.
妙なことが起こってる？
What weirdness?
「人の形をした黒い影が見えた」って報告が、うちの従業員からちょくちょく出てるの。
Some of my employees have been complaining about seeing a shadowy figure.
話によれば、最初は夢の中にそれが現れたんだけど、今は起きてる時も見えてるって――
They say it started with bad dreams, but now some are seeing it even when they're—
アーニャ！
Anya!
だ…大丈夫。それより…
I'm... fine, don't worry about me.
これ見て。
Look at this.
まったくもう、アンタはいつも大げさすぎ…ん？
Hmph. Course. You're just always being overly dramatic... huh?
おかしいな。現場の証拠品は警察が全部回収したはずなのに。
Weird. I figured the cops would have already collected all the evidence.
この近くに住んでるKFPの従業員で、被害者のことを知ってる者は？
Did any of your employees who live nearby know the victim?
いない。
Nope.
分かった。新しい情報が入ったらまた教えて。
Alright. Let me know if you hear anything else.
ちょっと待った！
Wait!
それだけ？私の時間を奪っておいてタダで帰るつもり？
That's it? You're not even gonna compensate me for my time?
従業員のためかと思いきや、結局カネかい。
I thought you were doing this to help your employees.
タダ働きはしない主義なの。
I'm still a businesswoman.
いま持ち合わせがないんだけど、代わりに歌で支払うっていうのはどう？
Well, I don't have any cash on me, but I can pay you in song.
ウソでしょ？歌うの？アンタと？
Seriously? You think I'd want to sing? With you?
イナは歌で喜んでくれたけどなー。
Ina accepted payment in song.
ただ、イナと歌うのは楽しいけど、
But then, singing with her is fun.
...is fun.
With you...
With me, what?
You don't think I'm good enough for you?!
Let's go, punk! You and me, right now!
全部全部あんたのせいだ
It's all, all your fault
反吐が出るくらいにウザったいわ
So annoying, it makes me want to throw up
何かにすがってへつらって
Clinging to something and flattering
期待したアタシが馬鹿だった
I was a fool to have expected anything
ご機嫌伺いのアパシー
Toadying apathy
それ故にアンチな一生ギミー
And thus, give me a lifetime of hate
浅いキャパシティ毎度おおきに
Shallow capacity, thanks as always
詰まるとこ人生ずっと地味
In short, my life is always plain
「憎らしい！」 「痛々しい！」
“Detestable!” “Pathetic!”
無視出来ないのが一層腹立たしい
The fact that I can't ignore it is even more irritating
苛立たしい そろそろ飽きた自画自賛に
Frustrating, I'm getting tired of your self-praise
ライクの反対はアパシー
The opposite of 'like' is apathy
イコールで繋がれた証
A proof of being connected with an equals sign
切り離せない関係
An inseparable relationship
逸らしてしまいたいわ
I just want to look away
これは所謂ヘイトスピーチ
This is a so-called hate speech
匿名性の声明を生命に乗せてんだ
Carrying an anonymous statement on my life
鳴り止まないサイレン 近づく度、痙攣
Unceasing siren, convulsing every time it gets closer
赤信号にずっと従順です
Always obedient to the red light
ねえ
Hey...
大体アナタのコト アタシ
Mostly, when it comes to you, I...
ダイダイダイダイダイキライ
Hate, hate, hate, hate, hate you!
omg 情けない 最早
OMG, how miserable, already
バイバイバイバイバイしたい
I want to say bye-bye-bye-bye-bye!
脳内も予測不能故に
Since even inside my brain is unpredictable
解解解 解は無い
Solve, solve, solve, there is no solution
どうだい？アタシのことアナタ
How about it? Do you...
ダイダイダイダイダイキライになった？
Hate, hate, hate, hate, hate me now?
あぁ百害あって一利ナシ nothing not see
Ah, a hundred harms and not a single benefit, nothing, not see
もしタラレバ並べてもニコチンだし
Even if we talk about 'what ifs', it's just nicotine
i miss you って近付いた結末は凡ミス 凡ミス
The ending that approached saying 'I miss you' is a simple mistake, simple mistake
センキュー反面教師 後味一生消えてくんないわ
Thank you, bad example, the aftertaste won't disappear for a lifetime
よしよし いい子ね
There, there, good girl
笑顔振り撒き パラパラ いい子ね
Scattering smiles, flutter, flutter, good girl
だけど だけど その本性は？
But, but, what is her true nature?
善悪の区別も付かないの？はぁ
Can't you even tell right from wrong? Sigh...
減点方式で取り巻く環境に巻かれて
Wrapped in an environment that surrounds with a demerit system
生涯、痛い！痛い！痛い！も聞こえないわ！って
In my lifetime, 'It hurts! It hurts! It hurts!' won't even be heard!
当然の報いにクラっちゃった
Hit by the natural retribution
人は鏡なんです
People are mirrors
実のところ依存は両辺です
To tell the truth, dependence is mutual
シャットダウンしても付き纏う
Even if you shut down, it follows you around
己の弱さが不甲斐ない
My own weakness is disappointing
全部全部あんたのせいって
It's all, all your fault
反吐が出るくらいに止まんないわ
So much that I want to throw up, it won't stop
いっその事 切り離した方が楽なのにね
Even though it would be easier to just cut you off
大体アナタのコト アタシ
Mostly, when it comes to you, I...
ダイダイダイダイダイキライ
Hate, hate, hate, hate, hate you!
omg 情けない 最早
OMG, how miserable, already
バイバイバイバイバイしたい
I want to say bye-bye-bye-bye-bye!
脳内も予測不能故に
Since even inside my brain is unpredictable
解解解 解は無い
Solve, solve, solve, there is no solution
どうだい？アタシのことアナタ
How about it? Do you...
ダイダイダイダイダイキライになった？
Hate, hate, hate, hate, hate me now?
あぁ百害あって一利ナシ nothing not see
Ah, a hundred harms and not a single benefit, nothing, not see
もしタラレバ並べてもニコチンだし
Even if we talk about 'what ifs', it's just nicotine
i miss you って近付いた結末は凡ミス 凡ミス
The ending that approached saying 'I miss you' is a simple mistake, simple mistake
センキュー反面教師 後味一生消えてくんないわ
Thank you, bad example, the aftertaste won't disappear for a lifetime
はぁ、もう、誰なの？
Sigh, who is it now?
はーい。
Come in.
アーニャ、ヤッホー。
Hey, Anya! Ya doing okay?
って、大丈夫そう？
Wait, are you okay?
なんか顔色悪いね。
You look kind of... not great.
大丈夫...じゃないかもね。
Thanks... maybe not.
ちょっと横になった方がいいんじゃない？
You just need sleep!
周りをぐるぐる走ってあげるから、わための数を数えるといいよ。
Lie down, and I'll run in circles so you can count me~
心配かけてごめん。
Sorry, but not now.
でも今寝たらダメなんだ。
I can't go to sleep right now.
なぜならあと、もうちょっとでこの事件を解決できそうなんだから！
I'm close to cracking this case wide open!
そう？
You sure?
そうかも、そうじゃないかも。
I don't know! Yes? Maybe?
わかんないけど、とりあえずヒントは揃ったんだ。
I do have all the hints...
ほな、難しいか。
That doesn't seem very sure...
わため先輩、程々にしておきましょう。
Watame-senpai, I think you're annoying her.
わためは悪くないよねぇー！
Watame did nothing wrong.
これが事件を解く鍵なんだ。探偵の直感がそう言ってる。
This is an important clue! I can feel it in my gut,
でもDNA鑑定では何もわからなかった。
but a DNA trace was a dead end.
じゃあ、これは何なんだ？！これは何なんだ？！
So what does it mean? What does it mean?!
その布でそんなにお困りなら...
That it's a mean cloth? If you're that troubled...
あ、じゃあ、わためが食べてあげる！
Oh! I could eat it.
ねえ、アーニャ、それちょっと見せてくれる？
Hey Anya? Can I take a look at that?
この布についてわかったことはあるけど...
If I tell you something about this cloth,
それを教えたら、ちょっと休憩しない？
will you agree to take a break?
一旦仕事の手は止めて、私たちと遊ぼうよ。
Maybe do something fun with us before you go back to work?
じゃあ一緒に歌でも歌う？
We could sing together.
この街では情報は歌で買うものみたいだし。
That seems to be the going rate for information around here.
おお、楽しそう！
Oh, that sounds fun!
おっけー。その布には魔力の痕跡を感じるんだ。
Alright... I can sense a magical residue on this cloth.
そんなバカな
That can't be true.
忘れたの？アイリスはネフィリム。
Hey, I'm a nephilim, remember?
魔力を感じとるなんてお手の物。
We get a bonus to detect magic!
あれ？アーニャもこの布が怪しいと思ってたんじゃないの？
Wait... you already had your suspicions about the cloth, didn't you?
そうだけどさー。
Yeeaaah... but...
でも殺人事件と超常現象なんて、混ぜたらだめなやつでしょ？
but supernatural stuff happening in a murder case? They're not supposed to mix.
そう？でもそういうアニメとかドラマも…
Really? But in some shows—
まあまあ、物騒な話はそのくらいにして。
Enough murder talk.
みんなで歌っちゃおう！
Let's sing~
この路地を抜けろ awake now
Get through this alley, awake now
僕ら 覚醒 アップデート ey
We awaken, update, ey
ギラギラ 光らせた
Make it shine brilliantly
いいな いいな そのカラット
So nice, so nice, that carat
目立っちゃうな 自然に 視線を 独り占め
Standing out, naturally monopolizing all eyes
この手口は盗めない
This technique can't be stolen
答えなら「好きなだけ」が極まってく
If it's an answer, "as much as you like" reaches its peak
一秒前完全アップデート ya ya
One second ago, a complete update, ya ya
不安グッバイ 自分以外は敵じゃない
Anxiety, goodbye, no one but myself is the enemy
お利口御無用指を立てろ
No need to be a good kid, raise your finger
ha～ 揺れろ 運命
ha~ Shake, destiny
ah～ あたしらしいウルトラ C
ah~ Ultra C, just like me
その感情を燃料に持ち込む延長戦へ全能
With that emotion as fuel, carrying our all-power into extra time
嗚呼、体が
Ah, my body...
この生き様で make some noise
Make some noise with this way of life
見舞う we gotta go メディカルボイス
We gotta go pay a visit, medical voice
宿した熱狂は伝播する 真っ向から着弾
The passion we harbor spreads, hitting right on target
もらうわ大歓声
I'll take the huge cheers
what i want to touch down
燃やせ 革命 アップデート hey
Burn, revolution, update hey
僕が覚醒、逆転 ey
I awaken, reversal, ey
ひとりきりじゃ just kidding
Just kidding on my own
君とだから dreaming
Because I'm with you, dreaming
間違いだらけ 勘違いもしてときめきをリテイク
Full of mistakes, even misunderstanding, retake that heartbeat
ey 失っても尚 コンティニュー
ey, even if I lose, still continue
支払った代償の自分 あの日に…してないわけない後悔
The self that paid the price, there's no way I don't regret that day...
胸に飾れ
Decorate your chest
前向き直せ 唱えて
Turn forward, fix it, recite it
（諦め悪いって？）信じてくれ
("Hard to give up?") Believe in me
青く燃ゆる 僕は炎
Burning blue, I am a flame
時は経てど 恋うは心
Time passes, but the heart still yearns
誰だ 誰だ 誰だ あたしだ さあお任せ
Who is it, who is it, who is it? It's me, leave it to me
この生き様で make some noise
Make some noise with this way of life
有終の美 get up! hey, raise the bro
Graceful end, get up! hey, raise the bro
宿した逆境に下克上 とうとう役満
Rebellion against the hardship, finally a grand slam
あげるわ 大団円
I'll give you a grand finale
what i want to touch down
燃やせ 革命 アップデート hey
Burn, revolution, update hey
go all out
僕が覚醒、逆転 ey
I awaken, reversal, ey
以上がこちらで調べた情報です。いかがですか？
So that's everything I've got so far. What do you think?
と、ここで、大空警察。
And so, here she visits the Oozora Police.
数々の難事件を解決してきた。
With their stellar track record of solving mysterious cases easily...
優秀な警察から、今回の事件に関するさらなる情報を得るべく、
in hopes of getting more information regarding this case from the excellent police force,
探偵は、警察署を訪れていた。
the detective visited the police station.
はっからー！事件の捜査は我々プロに任せておけばいいんだよ！
Oh, please! You should leave the investigation to us, the professionals!
何？被害者の服に魔力の痕跡があったって？
What? Magical residue was found on the victim's clothing?
そうだ！そんなバカな話があるか！
Exactly! How could such an absurd story be true?
こいつ、次、自分自身が凶器かもしれないとか言い出すんじゃないですか？署長。
Next, she's probably going to tell us that she herself might be the murder weapon, right, Chief?
それだ！
Wait, that's it!
はぁ？
Huh?
こいつ今、自分が凶器だって自白した？
Did she just confess to being the murder weapon?
よく分かんないっす。ボクが言ったのはただの冗談で...
I'm not sure. I was just joking about that... unless...
もしかしてボク、無意識のうちに真実をつかんでいたのか！？
What if I subconsciously knew the truth this whole time!
お前天才か！？
You are a genius!
おや、これはいよいよ事件解決・・になってしまうのか？
Oh my, could this possibly mean... the case is solved?
事件解決しちゃった！
I solved the case!
違う違う。私は凶器じゃないですよ。
I'm not the murder weapon.
異議あり！さっき自白しただろ！
OBJECTION! You already confessed!
私が言いたいのは、この事件にはまた別の古代兵器が関わっているかもしれないということ。
What I mean is, maybe there was another ancient weapon involved.
だから布に魔力が残っていたんだ。
That would explain the magical residue on the cloth.
なんだそういうことか…
I guess that makes sense.
僕が事件を解決できたと思ったのに…
But I wanted to solve the case...
まあ次がんばれよ。
You will solve the next one.
でもなぁ、現場の近くで変なものを見たっていう報告も届いてるんだ。
But we've also gotten reports of people seeing strange things near the murder scene.
その魔力の痕跡とやらが超常的な力によるものだっていうなら、変な幻覚が見えた人がいるのもそいつの影響ってこと？
If the involvement of something supernatural explains the magical residue, does it also cover those weird visions?
それはまだ分かりませんが、謎は必ず解いてみせましょう。
I'm not sure yet, but I'm going to find out.
じゃあうちの捜査資料を持って行っていいよ。
Then we will give you our case file to help out.
民間人にあげちゃダメっすよ！
You can't give that to a civilian!
でもこいつさぁ、なんか天才の匂いしね？
But she seems like a genius.
さっきはボクのこと天才って言ったじゃないですかぁ・・。
But you said I was a genius just a moment ago...
どんな情報でも助かりますよ。
Any information you have would be useful.
ただし！資料が欲しいなら、タダというわけにはいかんな！
Fiiine! But if you want our files, then we need something in return.
これ、また歌う流れですか？
Could that thing be, perhaps, a song?
おれは知らない 何も知らない
I don't know, I don't know anything.
何も見てない 誰も見てない
I didn't see anything, nobody saw anything.
空を見ても 見えない 夜の
Even if I look up at the sky, I can't see the night's...
欠けた月に 兎
...rabbit on the waning moon.
これはなんだ それが何か？
What is this? What is that anyway?
ここは楽し それでよろし
It's fun here, so that's good enough.
走る 逃げる 逃がす 逸らす
Run, flee, let go, look away,
月の欠けた場所へ
...to where the moon has waned.
あらら あらら あらら あらら あらら あらら
Oh dear, oh dear, oh dear...
妄想 止め処なく
Unstoppable delusions,
創造 咎めなく
...unreproached creations,
衝動 収まらず
...uncontrollable impulses.
なぜか なぜか なぜか なぜかしら
Why, why, why, I wonder why?
最悪だ！公序良俗を剥いで脱いで踊れ！
This is the worst! Strip away public order and morals and dance!
いや最低か！なんでなんでつって なんかなんか高鳴って
Or are you the lowest? Asking why, why, my heart is somehow pounding.
最悪だ！どうもこうもしねぇよ勝手にしやがれ！
This is the worst! There's nothing to be done, do whatever you want!
いや最低か！いやーもうほんと 最悪だ！だ！だ！だ！だ！
Or are you the lowest? No, seriously, it's the absolute worst!
ねてもさめてもつきまとう
Haunting me whether awake or asleep,
みえぬいしきのうらがわに
...behind my unseen consciousness,
おおきくあいたくろいあな
...a gaping black hole.
わかる わかる わかる
I understand, I understand, I understand.
許す 許せん 許す 許せん
Forgive, unforgivable, forgive, unforgivable.
かわいい えへへ むふふ こわい
Cute, hehe, mufu, scary.
りんご ごりら らくご ごじら
Apple, Gorilla, Rakugo, Godzilla,
らっぱ だぶら らまだ
Trumpet, Double, Ramada.
私たち絶対に見てません
We definitely didn't see anything!
言ってもせん 聞いてもせん 知ったこっちゃありません
We didn't say, we didn't hear, we don't care at all!
光を失し 影に一粒
Losing the light, a single drop in the shadow,
許されざる思考を
...an unforgivable thought.
当てはまらない異常を
With an abnormal state that doesn't fit in,
包んで生きていこうじゃありませんか
...why don't we wrap it up and keep on living?
葛藤 名も持たず
Conflict without a name,
狂騒 意味もなく
...frenzy without a meaning,
栄光 自己満足
...glory of self-satisfaction.
だから だから だからなんなのさ
So, so, so what about it?
最高だ！脳が凌駕してんだ ぶっ壊して叫べ！
This is the worst! My brain is overriding everything, break it and scream!
いや最高か！なんでなんでつって 舞いも舞いも跳ねちゃって
Or is it the best? Asking why, why, dancing and leaping around.
最高だ！降起降起で結構 勝手に生きたれ！
This is the worst! Rise up, rise up, it's fine, live however you want!
いや最高か！いやーもうほんと 最高だ！だ！だ！だ！だ！
Or is it the best? No, seriously, it's the absolute best!
むかしむかしのおもいづき
A whim from once upon a time,
むいみむいみのひとだかり
...a meaningless crowd of people,
むじゃきむてきのうまれつき
...innocent and invincible by nature.
それが それが それが
That is, that is, that is...
無責任に集合体
An irresponsible collective,
あんたも私も関係ない
...it has nothing to do with you or me.
無責任に集合体
An irresponsible collective,
楽しくやってりゃもう満開
...if we're having fun, we're in full bloom.
勝手にやってりゃ問題無し
If we do whatever we want, there's no problem.
おれは知らない 何も知らない
I don't know, I don't know anything.
何も見てない 何も見てない
I didn't see anything, nothing...
辛い
Painful...
疑問
Questions...
違い
Differences...
夢の話
Talks of dreams...
そういうこと？
Is that so?
それじゃ、
Well then...
超常的な力が殺人事件に関わっている？
A supernatural occurrence, happening in a murder case?
いやいやそんな、ねえ？
That's just unbelievable, right?
にわかには信じがたいが、今の手がかりから推理するとそういうことになる。
She had a hard time believing it, but all the hints said otherwise.
まだパズルのピースがピタリとはまらないこの不思議で奇妙な事件。
Still, there were pieces of this puzzle that refused to fit, this strange and bizarre case.
探偵は信頼できる情報源に頼ることにした。
So the detective turned to a reliable source for help.
あっ、来てくれたー
Ah, you came-
...なんで君達まで？
...And why are you guys also here?
ゼータが来るって聞いたから、アーニャにちょっかいかけてやろうと思って！
We heard Zeta was coming over, and decided to bug ya!
はいはい。
Yes, yes, I see.
もー！つれないなぁ。
Aww, come on!
それはそうと...ゼータ、何か掴めた？
Anyway, Zeta, did you find anything?
もちろん！優秀なシークレットエージェントなので！
Of course! I'm not an elite secret agent for nothing!
イナの描いた似顔絵と大空警察の資料から、被害者の身元を特定できたよ。
Between the portrait from Ina and the files from the Oozora Police, I've been able to positively ID the murder victim.
でも...ちょっと変なんだよね。
But... what I found is weird.
変？
How so?
被害者の履歴を調べたところ、その人物は何百年も前の時代の人だったんだ。
Well, when I investigated their history, I found that they actually lived centuries ago.
でもその人物が、数日前に死体で発見された...話がつながらないよ。
So how they were also somehow murdered just days ago... it doesn't make any sense.
アーニャからもらった情報に間違いがあったとか？
Did you perhaps confuse your information? Or...
なるほど、やっとつながってきた。
Actually, things are finally starting to make sense.
一人の被害者が、過去と現在で二度死んだことになる。
A victim caught between two times.
誰かが時間と次元をねじ曲げて、そんな状況を作り出した。
One who died in two different ways.
なかなかできることじゃない...
Not many exist who can cause time and dimensions to warp in a way to make that possible...
でも君なら可能でしょ。
...but you're one of them.
さすがは名探偵。
Well done, detective.
ちょっと時間がかかりすぎかな。危うくネタばらしするとこだった。
Took you long enough. I was this close to telling ya the whole thing.
レイネが書いてくれた、この匿名の手紙もいいヒントになったよ。
You helped enough with this "anonymous" letter about the murder.
えっ、バレてた？
O-oh, you figured out that was me?
書き方のクセで分かる。
I recognized your writing style.
待って、どういうこと？ムーナと被害者にどんな関係があるの？
W-wait, I don't get it. What does Moona have to do with the victim?
ムーナは、別の時空で殺された遺体を我々がいるこの時空へ移動させたんだ。
She took a murder victim from another space and time, and moved them into our dimension.
ゼータが特定した人物は、この世界線における同じ人物ってこと。
The one you ID'ed was this universe's version of the same person.
なるほど...？でもどうしてそんなことを？
Uh... okay. But then why?
理由も気になるけど、それより確かめたいことがある。
That is an important question, but there's one I want answered even more.
ムーナが...私にあの夢を見せたの？
Are you... responsible for my dreams?
それは違う。
No.
あなたがあの夢を見ていることを知って、私はあの夢が生まれる根源を調べてみた。
After I learned about your dreams, I used my powers to search for the source of them.
そして見つけたのが、次元の向こう側から声を届けようとする魂。
I found a spirit reaching out from time and dimensions.
私はその魂のために橋渡しをしてあげただけ...
All I've done is try to help them by making the bridge a little easier...
私も手伝ったよ！というか、私のアイデア。
With my help! I mean, it was my idea...
そう。
True.
ただやり方が悪かったのか、アーニャの見たものが他の人にも見えちゃったみたい。
Though doing it this way has caused some of what you've been experiencing to leak to other people.
巻き込んだKFPの従業員には後でお詫びしなきゃ...
We're going to have to apologize to the KFP workers...
でもその魂が、どうして私に声を届けようとしてるの？
But why is the spirit reaching out to me of all people?
それは私に訊くことじゃないね。私が話すべきことじゃない。
It wouldn't be right for me to answer those questions. It's not my story to tell.
あの魂に心を開いてあげて。それだけでいい。
Open yourself up to the spirits, and they'll do the rest.
心をもっと開く方法なら知ってるよ！
I got a way to make yourself more open to spirits!
それって歌？
Is it through song?
え？なんで分かったの？
Huh? How'd you know?
まあ、勘かな...
Lucky guess...
思い返していた 思い出の中で泣いていた
I was looking back, crying inside my memories.
不確かな夢と語録を掛け合って笑った
We laughed, multiplying our uncertain dreams and quotes.
この旅路も奇数も絶えないと 瞳を見返してスマイル仕様な
Hoping this journey and these odd moments won't end, I look back into your eyes and put on a smile.
焦りと不安が滲んで涙に呑まれてしまう
Impatience and anxiety seep in, and I end up swallowed by tears.
誰一人 欠けることはないチームはぐなっつ
Not a single person will be missing, Team Hagnuts.
僕らの思いが音になって繋ぐ
Our feelings turn into sound and connect us.
こだまして 忘れないよ 隠した秘密を
Echoing, I won't forget the secrets we hid.
あの日僕らは間違っていなかったんだと知る
Knowing that on that day, we weren't wrong.
閉ざして しまい込んだ 一線の光探して
Searching for a beam of light shut away and locked inside.
君の声を聞かせて
Let me hear your voice.
ここにいるって叫んでくれよ
Shout out that you are here!
その手を離さないで
Don't let go of that hand.
世界に僕だけ取り残されてしまう
Or I'll end up left behind all alone in this world.
...られたかな
...I could have lived easier.
暗闇の中で 立ち止まり 手放してしまう
Stopping in the darkness, I end up letting go.
心が通じ合えない 孤独感を 押し殺してしまうなら
If I must suppress this loneliness of not being understood...
1人でいた方が 楽に生きられたかな
...maybe it would've been easier to live alone.
憧れ
Longing...
理想に強く惹かれる感情が
These emotions strongly drawn to ideals...
僕らを引き寄せてしまうのなら
...if they draw us together...
応えて
Answer me.
くらまして
Dazzle me,
まだ終わっちゃいないんだ僕ら 延長戦だろう
We aren't done yet, this is extra time.
この音が途切れるまで
Until this sound completely fades out.
子供の頃に描いたヒーロー
The hero I imagined in my childhood...
君の出番が待ってる
...your turn is waiting.
くらまして
Dazzle me,
忘れないようかき鳴らした日々を
The days we played so we wouldn't forget...
あの日の僕らは間違っていなかったんだと知る
...letting us know we weren't wrong back then.
閉ざしてしまいこんだ
Locked away...
一閃の光探して
...searching for a flash of light.
君の声を聞かせて
Let me hear your voice.
ここにいるって叫んでくれよ
Scream out that you're right here.
その手を離さないで
Don't let go of my hand.
魂に心を開け？簡単に言ってくれる。
Opening up to the spirit? That was a tall order.
探偵になる前の彼女の人生において、他者に心を開くのは危険な行為だった。
In her life before being a detective, opening up to someone was dangerous.
今でもその本能は変わらない。
That instinct still lingers.
結局何も進展はなかった。
This was getting her nowhere.
謎はまだ残っているが、彼女はここのところ無理が続いていた。
She still had questions she needed answered, but maybe she had wound herself up too much.
少し休まなければ。
She needed a break.
Hello everyone! I'm Hatsune Miku, a virtual idol!
Well, that's what everyone seems to think... But secretly I'm a detective!
ええ？ミクちゃん？！
Eeh? Miku-chan?!
あ、アーニャちゃん！
Ah, Anya-chan!
一緒に歌おう！
Let's sing together!
わあー！
Wow!
I wake up to a call, put my frilly outfit on now
It's time I open up my eyes and start the day
I combat till the dawn, until every villain's gone, wah!
A clumsy trip and now I've fallen to my butt
With my magical phone and a silly little ringtone
I'll shout a magic word and set the world in place
Whatever it may cost, there's no reason to stop for a world that I cherish and love
Monsters might be a scary foe to fight, but I'll take the stand if I can stop your tears and wipe them dry
If my pain's a type of cure for peace, I don't mind, I can play as a nurse healing you everyday
So what if I might shed a tear, get some bruises? A wipe is all I need to clean the cherry blush away, ha!
Fighting through the night, but I'm wide awake
It can all be so hard for me to get through the day
Your smile is enough to heal all my aches
Wrapped in a cute band-aid, I can take the pain
Fight all day
Fill up the syringe with love, heal up the world and go again
Ur yaoi! Ur yaoi! Oooo fighter! Super powerful Miku-chan!
Ur yaoi! Ur yaoi! Oooo cyber! Miku Miku Miku go!
And now, it's time for the moment you've been waiting for!
1! 2! 3! Ready?! Miku Miku beam!
On my own without anyone to know
How my job's not all rainbows
But then I think about your smile
I'm a magically bright invincible girl! If you need me to heal, go on and call out my name
When you find yourself going down a spiral, I'll bonk away what puts you down, a pink hammer melee! Yah!
Fighting through the night, but I'm wide awake
All alone it's so hard for me to get through the rain
Your smile is enough to make my day
So I stand tall and brave 'cause I'm not afraid
Any pain I can laugh away
Chin up with love, I'll fight on till the end
Bearing through the pain, I'll try to be brave, as long as you can stay happy, I'm okay
あ、あ、眠いよ〜
Ah, I'm so sleepy...
I wake up to a call
put my frilly outfit on now
It's time I open up my eyes and start the day
I combat till the dawn
until every villain's gone, wah!
A clumsy trip and now I've fallen to my butt
With my magical phone
and a silly little ringtone,
I'll shout a magic word
and set the world in place
Whatever it may cost, there's no reason to stop,
for a world that I cherish and love
Oya oya oya oya, oh, fight on!
Super power, power of love, make a magic charge!
Miku miku miku miku go!
あー、眠いよ。
Ah, I'm so sleepy.
夢だった？！
It was a dream?!
知った
I knew...
救いのない形だった 僕の
...it was a helpless form, my...
知った
I knew...
狂いのない赤い血が 流れているんだ
...that error-free red blood is flowing inside me.
ただただ遅い来る影ばかり 目に満ちて
Only shadows attacking me fill my eyes,
からかう言葉 立ち上がれないような風
teasing words, a wind that won't let me stand up.
赤く光る地平へ
To the glowing red horizon,
裸足で駆けだしたら
if I start running barefoot,
ただ膝を抱えている君がいたから
you were there, just holding your knees.
だから
And so...
ENCOUNT 悲劇ぶった天国へ
Encountering toward a tragic heaven,
不甲斐ない瞳切ったあの日
on that day I cut my helpless eyes.
見つめた君のせい
It's because of you whom I stared at.
早く 早く 早く 早く 早く 早く 早く 早く
Hurry, hurry, hurry, hurry, hurry, hurry, hurry, hurry...
身を委ねて
surrender yourself.
奪い合う瞳 幾度
Eyes vying with each other, how many times...
崩れた貴方望む
have I wished for your broken self?
I can't wait to watch you lose it.
rotten, falling down
はやく はやく ねぇ教えて
Quickly, quickly... Hey, tell me?
調教 樹海 秘密のむこうへと
Training, a sea of trees, to the beyond of secrets.
SIX SENSE OOPARTS
Sixth sense, OOPArts.
不甲斐ない 瞳 きっとあの日
Those useless eyes... Surely, on that day...
みつめた 貴方のせいだ
it's because of you, who I gazed at.
はやく はやく
Quickly, quickly...
はやく息を止めて
Quickly hold your breath,
淡い淡い水面のむこうへと
to the beyond of the pale, pale water's surface.
白い光をみつめていると
When I gaze at the white light,
急な痛みに襲われる
I'm overcome by sudden pain.
僕は私を保っていられなくなること
Knowing I will no longer be able to maintain my self...
それをこの小さな器が証明している
this small vessel proves exactly that.
はじめに、安堵するきみがみたい
First, I want to see you relieved.
つぎに、期待したい
Next, I want to hope.
この場所で戦いなど起こっていない。
There was no major battle here.
少なくともこの世界線では...
At least not in this timeline...
だが探偵には分かっていた。彼女が見たものは決して夢ではないことを。
But the detective knows what she saw was no dream.
心の中にはまだ殺戮の匂いが漂っている。
The smell of the carnage still lingers in her mind.
かつての彼女にまとわりついていた、あの匂い。
It's a scent that was, at one time, so familiar to her.
探偵としての生活も今では順調だが、そうでなければあの匂いからは離れることができなかったでしょう。
That stench would still linger on her if the detective's life didn't take a turn for the better.
今でも... あの頃の日々がリアルな夢のようにまとわりつく。
Even now... her days felt more like the real dream.
終わるべくして終わったおとぎ話。
A fairytale. Maybe one that deserved to end.
どこまで行っても彼女は、生まれ持った本質から逃れることはできない。
Because, at the end of the day, she can never run away from her nature.
それでも今は違う。今の彼女には仲間がいる。
But she's not just that anymore. She has friends to thank for that.
それが、別の世界線の彼女とは違う点なのかもしれない。
Maybe that was what separated her from the other version.
もしかしたらあの子は、幸せに生きることのできた世界線があったのだろうかと、
And, maybe... that version of herself just wanted a ray of hope,
そんな一筋の希望を求めていたのだろうか。
to know that there was one timeline where things worked out.
そしてその幸せな世界線というのは、ここではないまた別の世界線のことかもしれない...
Or perhaps this was never about the detective...
考えが頭を巡るものの、答えが出ることはない。
so many thoughts run amok inside her head, but they're forever left unanswered.
何にせよ、探偵は自身の血塗られた過去を忘れることはないでしょう。
Whatever the case, the detective won't forget her bloody past,
しかしまた後戻りするつもりもない。
but she isn't going to revert to it either.
彼女はこれからも仲間とともに進む。
She will continue to move forward with her friends,
望んだ結末を迎えられなかった別の自分たちのためににも。
and for all the variants who didn't get their desired ending.
探偵アーニャ・メルフィッサは、
The detective, Anya Melfissa,
明日に向かって生き続ける。
will keep on living for her own tomorrow.
Anya Melfissa Birthday Live 2024!
How did everyone like it? Oh my goodness!
やっと今年も参りました、アーニャの誕生日です！いかがでしたでしょうか？
Anya's birthday has finally come around again this year! How did you all like it?
This time, I tried to incorporate a little bit of story into my 3D birthday celebration. And I think it turned out pretty nice, you know?
You get story part and also live part, and I think it turned out pretty well!
And also, how was my new original song? Oh my goodness! How was my new original song? It was good, wasn't it? I hope you all liked it!
新曲もね、あの、歌わせていただきました。いかがでしたでしょうか？
I got to sing my new song too. How did you all like it?
Ah! Oh my god!
I celebrated...
...um, I celebrated...
...my birthday with...
...a lot of friends too this year!
Yeah!
A lot of the girls came to celebrate my birthday.
And also Detective Anya managed...
...to solve that mission. Wow, she's got it!
Detective Anya!
Did you guys like Detective Anya as well?
Detective Anya was pretty cool, but not as cool as me!
Oh my god! And also, special guests!
There were special guests!
Oh my god, I can't believe I got to sing with Hatsune Miku!
Hatsune Miku-chan!
Oh my god, she was really cute!
And also, for the narration for my story part...
...Ueda Reina-san narrated!
Oh my god! Ueda Reina-san also...
ナレーションね、ストーリーパートのナレーションもね、
...narrated the story part as well!
上田麗奈さんが、えー、やってくれました！
Ueda Reina-san did it for us!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
ミクちゃんとも歌ったし、
I sang with Miku-chan too.
いや、盛りだくさんでしたね、今年。
Wow, it was so packed this year!
Oh my god, lots of wild things happening...
...on this year's birthday live.
How did you guys like it?
How did you guys like it? Oh my gosh!
Yeah, I had a lot of fun!
But...
I would like to make an announcement this year!
It's the usual.
ここで告知があります！
I have an announcement here!
I have an announcement to make! Let me make an announcement!
はい、こちら！
Yes, this is it!
Oh my god, what is that? Who is that? Is that me? Yes, it is!
We're releasing...
...some new merchandises too this year!
What do we have? Let's take a look at them, shall we?
そして、えーっと、1つずつ見ていきましょう。
Let's take a look at them one by one.
まずは、こちらです！
First up is this one!
Whoa, it's a canvas art!
Study Time with Anya Canvas Art!
Oh my god, this illustration is so cute!
It's illustrated by Lunar-sensei.
Lunar先生に、イラストを描いていただきました。可愛い！
The illustration was drawn by Lunar-sensei. So cute!
The theme is, you know...
...literary girl.
Oh my god, so smart, so intelligent!
(Giggles)
文学少女というテーマになっております。
The theme is a literary girl.
次はこちら！
Next is this!
Study Time with Anya, the Notebook!
I think this is my first notebook.
I've never had a notebook as a merchandise before, oh my goodness!
I've never had a merchandise notebook before, oh my goodness!
Please use this lots...
...for all your notes, for anything!
いろいろメモしてね。オリジナルノートです。出ます。
Write lots of notes! It's an original notebook.
と、次はこちら！
And next is this!
Ah! It's a pen case!
How cute is that?
ペンポーチです！
It's a pen pouch!
ペンポーチも初かな？
Is this the first pen pouch too?
ノートも初らしい、ペンポーチもなんと、えー、初です！
It seems the notebook is a first, and so is the pen pouch!
ぜひ一緒にね、あの、ノートと使ってください。
Please use it together with the notebook!
Um, use this...
...along with the notebook. I think they would go...
...really well together, okay?
次はこちら！
Next is this!
今年もボイスが出ます！
We have a voice pack this year too!
そして今年も、えー、アーニャが台本を書かせていただいております！
And this year too, Anya wrote the script!
I wrote the script, as usual...
...as usual for every year.
I wrote the script for this situational voice...
...so please get it!
Please get it!
Oh yeah, the voice will be in Japanese, but there will be scripts...
...in Bahasa Indonesia, English, and Japanese.
ちなみにボイス自体は日本語になりますけど、
By the way, the voice itself is in Japanese,
えーっと、台本も付いて、付いてきます。
but it also comes with the script.
インドネシア語と英語と、日本語の台本があります。
The scripts are available in Indonesian, English, and Japanese.
ぜひ聴いてください。
Please listen to it!
そしてフルセット購入特典はこちら！
And here is the bonus for purchasing the full set!
Oh my god! Limited Edition has...
...what is that? A hand-signed autograph?
Oh my god, it's a first for me!
Anya's first ever hand-signed autograph...
...for Limited Edition. Please get them!
なんと今年はサイン入りです！
It actually includes an autograph this year!
今年はサイン入りです。なんと、なんと、なんと！
It's autographed this year. Wow, wow, wow!
初、初ですね。アーニャが自らサインをして、
It's a first, yes. Anya is personally signing them,
初なので、ぜひ皆さん、この機会でゲットしてください！
and since it's the first time, everyone, please get it on this occasion!
Yeah! Please get the Limited Edition.
And for the Standard Edition...
...it includes a foil-stamped replica autograph.
So don't worry if you miss out on the Limited Edition!
Yay!
ということでグッズ紹介は以上です。
And that's all for the merchandise introduction!
...introduction.
And another announcement is
that my original song, the one that you guys heard...
um, it's called ENCOUNT or En-count, by the way,
it will be releasing digitally...
It will be releasing digitally in like a few hours.
It will be releasing digitally
at 12:00 AM your time zone, at 13 March.
at 12:00 AM your time zone, on March 13th.
Yay! Yippee!
So, in like... in like a few hours, yeah.
Yay! なんとね、デジタルリリース、
Yay! Actually, the digital release,
新曲のデジタルリリースもあります！
the digital release for the new song is also coming!
13日の0時です。
It's at midnight on the 13th.
よろしくおねがいします！
Please check it out!
そして、この後、
And after this,
メンバーシップで配信もするので、ぜひ見てください。
I'll be streaming on membership, so please watch it!
There will be a special encore
for members only after this!
So, members, my homies, let's go!
There will be a membership-only stream after this!
So please come and watch.
It will be in 3D, by the way.
So you guys might want to check it out.
Yippee!
Okay, are you guys ready? Are you guys ready?
Well, this live is ending but we still have membership after this.
So I will see you guys there!
For members, I will see you guys there.
And for non-members, thank you so much for coming
and for watching my 3D birthday live!
I hope you guys enjoyed it!
Thank you, thank you!
And I wonder if you guys also posted a lot
using the hashtag? I sure hope you guys did.
Yeah, thank you so much!
And... おつくりーす！ バイバイ！
And... Otsu-keris! Bye-bye!
おつくりーす、everyone!
Otsu-keris, everyone!